Guide to the Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1,
5583/1
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
120 linear ft.
Records (documents), publications (documents).
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Publications, manuals, policies, and plans issued by a large sample of Fortune 500 corporations and by a variety of organizations, such as professional and trade associations, government agencies, and educational and cultural organizations. The materials issued by corporations include company histories, employee newsletters, employee benefit plans, personnel practice manuals, performance appraisal forms, affirmative action policies, training brochures, job descriptions, and career development programs as well as national trade association documents and recruitment material.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Several economic activities(sectors) are represented in the collection, such as manufacturing, transportation, mining, banking, insurance, utilities, trade, and services. Corporations whose pamphlets are held in the collection include AT&T, Bethlehem Steel, Bell Telephone System, Firestone Tire & Rubber, Ford Motor Co., General Electric, General Foods, General Mills, General Motors, Goodyear Tire & Rubber, Heinz, International Harvester, Johnson & Johnson, Lockheed Aircraft Co., Maytag Co., Metropolitan Life Insurance Co., National Association of Manufacturers, Pennsylvania Railroad Co., Radio Corporation of America (RCA), Standard Oil, Tennessee Valley Authority, Union Carbide, and Westinghouse Electric among numerous other corporations.
Due to the volume of material in this collection the finding aid has been divided into six sections.
Section 1: Boxes 1-22
Section 2: Boxes 23-44
Section 3: Boxes 45-66
Section 4: Boxes 67-88
Section 5: Boxes 89-110
Section 6: Boxes 111-121
SUBJECTS
Names:
A. Philip Randolph Institute.; Abbott Laboratories.; Abbott Laboratories. House Organs.; Abraham & Straus.; Addressograph-Multigraph Corporation.; Administrative Management Society.; Adult Education Association.; Aero Supply Mfg. Co.; Aerojet-General Corporation.; Aeroquip Corporation.; Aerospace Industries Association of America.; Aetna Life Insurance Company (Hartford, Conn.); Affiliated Schools for Workers.; African- American Labor Center.; Agway Inc.; Air Reduction Company.; Air Transport Association of America.; Airlines Negotiating Committee.; Alaska. Department of Administration.Division of Personnel.; Alden's, Inc.; Alexander Smith & Sons, Carpet Co.; Allegheny Ludlum Steel Corporation.; Allegheny Metal.; Allied Chemical & Dye Corporation; Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company.; Aluminum Company of America.; American Arbitration Association.; American Brake Shoe Company.; American Can Company.; American Labor Education Service.; American Locomotive Company.; American Management Association.; American Merchant Marine Institute.; American Metal Climax, Inc.; American Motors Corporation.; American Petroleum Institute.; American Plan Association.; American Society of Safety Engineers.; American Telephone and Telegraph Company.; American Textile Manufacturers Institute.; American Thread Company.; American Trucking Associations.; American Type Founders Company.; American Vocational Association.; Americans Against Union Control of Government.; Amtrak.; Anaconda American Brass Company.; Anaconda Company.; Anaconda Copper Mining Company.; Anaconda Wire and Cable Company.; Anchor Hocking Glass Corporation.; Armco Steel Corporation.; Armour and Company.; Armstrong Cork Company.; Associated Builders & Contractors (U.S.); Associated General Contractors of America.; Association of American Railroads.; Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railroad Company.; Atlantic Refining Company.; Atlas Chemical Industries.; ATO, Inc.; Automobile Manufacturers Association.; Automotive and Aviation Parts Manufacturers.; Automotive Council for War Production.; Bell & Howell Co.; Bell Aircraft Corporation.; Bell of Pennsylvania.; Bell Telephone Company.; Bell Telephone Laboratories.; Bethlehem Steel Corporation.; Bird and Son, Inc.; Bituminous Coal Operators' Association.; Bloomer Brothers.; Boeing Aerospace Company.; Boeing Company.; Borden Company.; Brockway Glass Company.; Building Trades Employers' Association.; Bureau of National Affairs (Arlington, Va.); Burlington Industries, Inc.; Burndy Engineering Company.; Burrough Corporation.; California Institute of Technology. Industrial Relations Center.; California Institute of Technology.; California State Personnel Board.; Canadian National Railways; Canadian Pacific Railway Company.; Carborundum Company (Niagara Falls, N.Y.); Carnation Company.; Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation.; Carrier Corporation.; Caterpillar Tractor Company.; Celanese Corporation.; Central Hudson Gas and Electric Corporation.; Chamber of Commerce of the United States of America.; Chemical Corn Exchange Bank.; Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company.; Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company of Maryland.; Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company of Virginia.; Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company.; Chessie System, inc.; Chicago Transit Authority.; Chrysler Corporation.; Cincinnati Bell Inc.; Civil Service Assembly of the United States and Canada.; Climax Molybdenum Company.; Clothing Manufacturers Association of the U.S.A.; Colgate-Palmolive Company.; Colorado Fuel and Iron Company.; Columbia Gas Company.; Commerce and Industry Association of New York.; Committee for the Nation's Health.; Commonwealth Edison Company.; Communications Workers of America.; Cone Mills Corporation.; Connecticut General Life Insurance Company.; Consolidated Edison Company of New York, inc.; Consolidated Gas, Electric Light, and Power Company of Baltimore.; Consolidated Natural Gas Company.; Consolidated Vultee Aircraft Corporation.; Consumers' League of New York City.; Consumers Power Company (Mich.); Container Corporation of America.; Continental Can Company.; Continental Insurance Company.; Continental Oil Company.; Cooperative League of the U.S.A.; Corn Products Refining Company.; Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory.; Cornell University.; Corning Glass Works.; Council Against Communist Aggression (U.S.); Council for International Progress in Management (USA); Council of Profit Sharing Industries (U.S.); Crane Co.; Crane Packing Co.; Credit Union National Association.; Crouse-Hinds Company.; Crown Zellerbach Corporation.; Crucible Steel Company of America.; Dan River Mills Inc.; Dartnell Corporation.; Daystrom, inc.; Dartnell Corporation.; Deere & Company.; Detroit Edison Company.; Diamond Alkali Company.; Dictaphone Corp.; Dole Food Company.; Douglas Aircraft Company.; Dow Chemical Company.; E.I. du Pont de Nemours & Company.; Eagle Pencil Company.; Eastern Gas and Fuel Associates.; Eastern Western & Southwestern Canier Company.; Eastman Kodak Company.; Eaton Corporation.; Eaton Manufacturing Company.; Ecusta Paper Company.; Electronic Industries Alliance.; Eli Lilly and Company.; Employers' Association of Chicago.; Employers' Association of Detroit.; Employers' Association of Grand Rapids.; Employers' Association of Massachusetts.; Employers' Association of Milwaukee.; Employers' Association of Pittsburgh.; Employers' Association of Washington.; Employers' Group of Insurance Companies.; Employers' Labor Relations Information Committee.; Employers' of Mutual of Wasau.; Engineers Joint Council. Engineering Manpower Commission.; Erie Railroad Company.; Erie-Lackawanna Railroad Company.; Erlanger Mills, Inc.; Erwin Cotton Mills.; Esso Research and Engineering Company.; Esso Standard Oil Company.; Exxon Corporation; Falstaff Brewing Corporation; Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America; Federal Professional Association (U.S.); Federal Reserve Bank of New York; Federated Employers of San Francisco; Federated Employers of the Bay Area; Fieldcrest Mills Inc.; William Filene's Sons Co.; Firestone Tire and Rubber Company; First National Bank (Ithaca, N.Y.); First National Bank Maryland; First National Bank of Boston; First National Bank of Chicago; First National Bank of Portland (Portland, Me.); First National Bank of St. Louis; First Pennsylvania Bank, N.A.; First Pennsylvania Banking and Trust Company, Philadelphia.; Fischer and Porter Company; Florida Power & Light Company; Ford Foundation; Ford Motor Company; Foster and Forbes Glass Company; Foundation for Economic Education, inc.; General Dynamics Corporation.; General Electric Company; George Fischer, Ltd.; J.N. Adam & Company.; New Jersey Bell Telephone Company.; New York Chamber of Commerce.; Society for Equitable Assurances on Lives and Survivorships.; South Central Bell.; University of California, Berkeley. Institute of Industrial Relations.; William Filene's Sons Co.; Commonwealth Edison Company; A. Philip Randolph Institute; ATO, Inc.; Aero Supply Mfg. Co.; Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
Subjects:
Adult education; Aeronautics; Agricultural industries; Aluminum industry and trade; Airlines; Aircraft industry; Agricultural machinery; Architectural metal-work; Audio equipment industry; Automobile industry and trade; Arbitration, Industrial; Agricultural chemicals industry; Audio equipment industry; Bituminous materials industry; Building trades; Buildings--Environmental engineering; Banks and banking; Breweries; Baked products industry; Business consultants; Clothing trade; Coal mines and mining; Chemical industry; Compressor industry; Clerks (Retail trade); Computer industry; Cereal products; Consumer protection; Container industry; Credit unions; Clay industries; Cement industries; Copper alloys; Dairy products industry; Detergent industry; Executives--Training of; Electric power transmission; Electronics industries; Food industry and trade; Frozen foods and industry; Footwear industry; Fruit trade; Farm produce--Marketing--Government policy; Finance, Public; Glass container industry; Glass manufacture; Gas extraction; Grain trade; Grocery trade; Gasket industry; Human capital; Hydroelectric power plants; Life insurance.; Iron industry and trade; Property insurance.; Casualty insurance.; Instructional materials industry; Health insurance.; Investment banking; Infant formula industry; Knit good industry; Labor unions; Local transit; Luggage industry; Logging; Medical supplies industry; Medicaid; Motor vehicle industry; Metal trade; Meat industry and trade; Military vehicle industry; Medical instruments and apparatus industry; Management; Measuring instruments; Natural gas pipelines; Notions (Merchandise); Newspaper publishing; Navigation equipment industry; National security; Office management; Office equipment and supplies; Petroleum refineries; Photographic industry; Paper folding (Graphic design); Public utilities; Paper products industry; Political participation; Plastics industry and trade; Pharmaceutical industry; Paint industry and trade; Public administration; Public opinion polls; Paper bag industry; Retail trade; Rug and carpet industry; Railroads; Rubber industry and trade; Railroad equipment industry; Roller bearings; Security systems industry; Service industries; Social security; Shipment of goods; Sanitary supply industry; Soybean industry; Slaughtering and slaughter-houses; Transportation equipment industry.; Telecommunication.; Trucking industry.; Trucks--Design and construction.; Textile industry.; Trade associations.; Tobacco industry.; Universities and colleges.; Vocational education.; Wood products.; Welding equipment industry.; Woolen goods industry.
Form and Genre Terms:
Records (documents); Publications (documents)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Other sections of this Collection:
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 1: Boxes 1-22
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 3: Boxes 45-66
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 4: Boxes 67-88 5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 5: Boxes 89-110
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 6: Boxes 111-121
Related Collections:
5880: Archives Organization File V, Additional Company Documents
5583/2: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2
5583/3: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3
5583/4: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 4. Corporate and Organizational Publications
5583/5: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 5
5583/6: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 6
5956: Archives Organization File Additional records
CONTAINER LIST
- Box: 23, Folder: 1 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Initial Training for Service Representatives, Publication (Box 23, Folder 1)
    By Pennsylvania Bell Telephone Company. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Initial Training Guide for Business Office Representatives, Publication (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Box: 23, Folder: 2 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Leader's Outline and Text Material for Discussion on Let's Talk About Business, Publication (Box 23, Folder 2)
    By Bell Telephone Company of Pennsylvania. Item is in English.
- Box: 23, Folder: 3 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Summar of Bell System Savings Plan for Salaried Employees, Publication (Box 23, Folder 3)
    By Bell of Pennsylvania. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Maternity Payment Plan, Publication (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: Your Dental Protection, Publication (Box 23, Folder 3)
    By Bell of Pennsylvania Diamond State Telephone. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Summary Plan Description of the Bell System Savings and Security Plan for Non-Salaried Employees, Publication (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: Summary Plan Description of the Bell System Employee Stock Ownership Plan (ESOP), Publication (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Your Medical Protection, Publication (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Item 7: You and Business, Publication (Box 23, Folder 3)
    By The Bell Telephone Company of Pennsylvania The Diamond State Telephone Company. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Your Group Life Insurance Protection, Publication (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Item 9: Your Medical Protecection, Publication (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Item 10: Summary of plan for employees' pensions, diability benefits and death benefits, Publication (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Item 11: Long Term Disability Plan (non-salaried), Publication (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Item 12: Summar of Long Term Disability Plan For Salaried Employees, Publication (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Box: 23, Folder: 4 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Better Benefits for you and your Family, Publication (Box 23, Folder 4)
    By South Central Bell. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: South Central's Tuition Plan for Employees, Publication (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: Special medical Expense Plan Providing protection after age 65, Publication (Box 23, Folder 4)
    By South Central Bell Telephone Company. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: For Your Security, Publication (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: Extraordinary Medical Expense Plan, Publication (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: Plan for Employees' Pensions Disability Benefits and Death Benefits, Publication (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Item 7: Employees With Drinking Problems a Management Guide, Publication (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Item 8: Our Personal Responsibility, Publication (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Item 9: Headquarters Personnel, Personnel-Benefit Committee, Personnel Medical, Headquarters Personnel - Labor Relations, Publication (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Item 10: Basic Medical Expense plan, Publication (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Item 11: Equal Opportunity Employee's Guide to the Equal Opportunity Agreement with the Federal Government, Publication (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Item 12: Jobs, Publication (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Box: 23, Folder: 5 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Code of Conduct, Publication (Box 23, Folder 5)
    By Southern New England Telephone. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: job opportunities with a future, Publication (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: The First Century of the Telephone in Connecticut, Publication (Box 23, Folder 5)
    By Reuel A. Benson, Jr. Item is in English.
- Box: 23, Folder: 6 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Summary of Plan for Employees' Pensions, Disability Benefits and Death Benefits, Publication (Box 23, Folder 6)
    By Southern Bell. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: A Short History Of Southern Bell, Publication (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: Perspective: Meet the latest, hottest telephone topic - measured service, Publication (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: Views, Publication (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Item 5: Management Information Bulletin, Publication (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Item 6: Guidelines for Controlling Absences, Publication (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Box: 23, Folder: 7 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Job Evaluation Plan For Management Employees, Publication (Box 23, Folder 7)
    By Southwestern Bell. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: tuition plan for telephone people, Publication (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Item 3: History of the Southwestern Bell Telephone Company, Publication (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Box: 23, Folder: 8 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Safery Items, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
    By Green Cross for Safety. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Safery Items, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Item 3: Safery Items, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Item 4: Safery Items, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Item 5: Facts about teenage drinking and driving, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
    By Family Safety. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Safery Items, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Item 7: That Abominable Snow, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
    By Bell Telephone Laboratories. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Turnpike Turnabout, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Item 9: A Handbook of Child Safety, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Item 10: It Cuold Happen to Your Child, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Item 11: Only One Pair to A Customer, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Item 12: Hold Everything, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Item 13: Manual of Safety Practices, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Item 14: Safety Practices, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Item 15: Safety Meeting Material, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Item 16: Seat Belt Program, Publication (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Box: 23, Folder: 9 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Historic Firsts, Publication (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Box: 23, Folder: 10 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Summary of Benefits, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
    By Bethlehem Steel Corp. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: One Bell System. It Works., Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
    By Bell Telephone Labs. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Ohio Bell's Aducational Assistance Plan, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
    By Bell Telephone. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: The Tuition Aid Plan, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
    By Cincinnati Bell. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: A Look at Bell Labs, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Item 6: Facts About Bell Laboratories, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
    By Western Electronic Inc. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Get A Personal, Authoritative Answer, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Item 8: The Dilemma of Bell Labs Older Professional - Is It "Age Discrimination"?, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
    By CPTP. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Salary Survey of The Associate & Members of Staff of Bell Telephone Laboratories, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Item 10: Salary Survey of The Associate & members of Staff of Bell Telephone Laboratories Part II, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Item 11: Facts About Bell Laboratories, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Item 12: Evaluating Scientific Personnel, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Item 13: Management/Employee/Union, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Item 14: Here is The Information You Wanted from Bell Laboratories, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Item 15: Services at Bells Labs, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Item 16: An Introduction to Careers with the Bell System, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Item 17: Union-Management Relationships, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Item 18: MTAP Career Development Through Training at C&P, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Item 19: Educational Assistance Plan for Management Employees, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Item 20: Your Benefits, Publication (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Box: 23, Folder: 11 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Safeguard, Publication (Box 23, Folder 11)
    By Wisconsin Telephone Co. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: A Challenge Right From The Start, Publication (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Item 3: PhoneCenter, Customers can 'be choosey' on Broadway, Publication (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Item 4: PSC Limits Scope of Rate Case Hearings, Publication (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Item 5: Realignment Effort Gets Underway, Publication (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Box: 23, Folder: 12 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Employee Magazine Ideas, Publication (Box 23, Folder 12)
    By Bemis Bro. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Study of Informal Pension Costs At Indianapolis Bleaching Company, Publication (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Item 3: Merit Rating, Publication (Box 23, Folder 12)
- Box: 23, Folder: 13 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: occupational Hazards and Black Workers, Publication (Box 23, Folder 13)
    By Berkley Labor Occupational Health Program. Item is in English.
- Box: 23, Folder: 14 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Rules and Benefits for Employees of Beth Israel Hospital, Publication (Box 23, Folder 14)
    By Beth Israel Hospital. Item is in English.
- Box: 23, Folder: 15 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Bethlehem Supervisory Safety Manual, Publication (Box 23, Folder 15)
    By Bethlehem Steel. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Introduction to Accident Prevention 1, Publication (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Item 3: The Nature, Causes, and Results of Accidents 2, Publication (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Item 4: Accident Prevention Principles and Responsibilities 3, Publication (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Item 5: Accident Investigation reporting and Follow-Up 4, Publication (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Item 6: Control of Environmental Hazards, Publication (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Item 7: Planned Safety Inspections, Publication (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Item 8: Preventing Basic Types of Accidents, Publication (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Item 9: Developing Safe Job Procedure, Publication (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Item 10: Employee Job Safety Training 9, Publication (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Item 11: Planned Safety Observations 10, Publication (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Item 12: Motivating Employees to Work Safely, Publication (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Item 13: Handling Safety Problem Employees, Publication (Box 23, Folder 15)
- Box: 23, Folder: 16 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Handbook of Information Concerning Salaried Employees, Publication (Box 23, Folder 16)
    By Bendix-Westinghouse. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Products & Services Directory, Publication (Box 23, Folder 16)
    By Bendix. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Sales-Engineering Service Training, Publication (Box 23, Folder 16)
    By Scintilla Magneto Division. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Training Program, Publication (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Item 5: Training, Publication (Box 23, Folder 16)
    By Bendix Aviation Corporation. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Orientation Program, Publication (Box 23, Folder 16)
    By Scinitilla Magneto Division. Item is in English.
- Box: 23, Folder: 17 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: A Career, and How to Make Good in It, Publication (Box 23, Folder 17)